Matthias Mullie Full-stack engineer

Koeksken 63 8531 Bavikhove, BE +32 472 42 89 94 matthias@mullie.eu www.mullie.eu

I'm a senior software engineer with an appetite for complex problems. I'm easy going & take responsibility for my work. Most of my expertise is with PHP, Python, MySQL, JavaScript & related tech, but I like to fiddle with <shiny-new-toy> when I have a chance.

I care about code architecture. I love hard challenges, clean code & learning new things. Bonus points for open source projects. I play soccer & like to travel.

Experience

Wikimedia Foundation

San Francisco, USA (remote) 2012 – present

Senior software engineer

I'm involved in projects to increase editor participation on Wikipedia, like Flow: a modern discussion/collaboration system.

Most fun lies in architecting robust solutions for the unconventional challenges we face in terms of performance & scalability, taking away most of the headaches to ensure we can build new features at a fast pace.

PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, memcached, Redis, Elasticsearch, SASS, LESS, handlebars, OOP, scalability, code review, GIT, PHPUnit, Scrum, ...

Wijs

Ghent, BE 2008 – 2012

Lead developer

I lead the projects of our clients and made sure they ship flawlessly. I enjoyed being responsible for my team and building great stuff together.

In my second role as product owner of Fork CMS, I lead its technical direction, defined priorities & assigned resources to grow this open-source project.

PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, memcached, Symfony, Composer, OOP, DNS, GIT, APIs, accessibility, SEO, waterfall, ...

Blade fx

Kuurne, BE 2008

Web developer

Starting from the design, I sliced it up & implemented the websites with the company's proprietary framework.

ASP, MSSQL, HTML, CSS, Photoshop, DNS

Education

Katho

Kortrijk, BE 2004 – 2011

Bachelor in Applied Computer Science

ASP.NET, Java, Oracle DB, HTML, CSS, XML, Networking, OOP, ...

VDAB

Wevelgem, BE 2007 – 2008

PHP developer

PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, XML

Sint-Amandscollege

Kortrijk, BE 2002 – 2004

IT Management

ASP.NET, VB.NET, HTML, CSS, Networking

Spes Nostra Institute

Heule, BE 1998 – 2002

Latin-Math

Math and stuff

Independent courses

Mark Pilgrim Dive Into Python 3

2014 And various other Python resources & exercises.

King Foo Getting Started with Symfony2

2013

Stanford Online A Crash Course on Creativity

2013

Open source

I've had the fortune of working in somewhat open source minded companies. A lot of my work is "out in the open", most of which is on (or mirrored on) GitHub: github.com/matthiasmullie

The projects I've worked on the most:

mediawiki.org
fork-cms.com
minifier.org

Certification

Sun Certified MySQL 5.0 Developer

2010

Zend Certified Engineer PHP 5 & PHP 5.3

2010

Online

mullie.eu witter.com/matthiasmullie in linkedin.com/in/matthiasmullie

🕥 github.com/matthiasmullie 📑 stackoverflow.com/users/802993 📑 facebook.com/matthias.mullie.3

орепhub.net/accounts/matthiasmullie